<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-16T19:39:03-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Haosong Liu’s  Blog</title><subtitle>M.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering @University of Miami. Japanese anime and classical music lover. Passionate about Software Engineering.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/07/16/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2020-07-16T14:41:03-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T14:41:03-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/07/16/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/07/16/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My First Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/some/random/stuff/2020/07/16/My-First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Post" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/some/random/stuff/2020/07/16/My-First-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/some/random/stuff/2020/07/16/My-First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;I have finally decided to set-up a personal blog website, although I have, a long time ago, already knew how to build a simple blog webiste. Why so late? Well, partly because of the process of getting a domain name in China is a little bit complicated, partly(and largely) because I’m lazy and don’t want to spend money just for hosting a simple Blog website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, things changed a bit when I started to look for jobs. I reckon it’d be better to have a place where I can really shocase my stuff and thoughts to the world. This is when I feel it might be a good idea to set-up a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trigger for me to do such a thing is a zoom-meeting with my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://zishiwu123.github.io/&quot;&gt;Zishi Wu&lt;/a&gt; who also decided to start looking for SDE/Data Analysis jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to COVID-19, finding a job is becoming really hard. Zishi was born and raised in U.S. and took a gap year before doing his PhD whereas I’m an international student who spent my undergrad years studying Material Science and did not even think about going to the industry before realizing Material Science is not for me and changed gear to Computer Science. Therefore, his advice is definitely invaluable for me. One of his advice is to do some project and deploy it to the web so you can showcase to people what you have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason for me to start my personal blog is that I have already written some blogs on CSDN, a Chinese IT blog forum. However, I always find it annoying accessing CSDN from U.S. because of the laggings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first tried to build this website from scratch using Flask because I had done similar things before as a side project so I have some experience. However, I’m really really bad at UI/UX design (I’m more into logic rather than visual art), so it bugs me a lot when I try to modify the template design in Flask as I find it both difficult(as my graphic design ability is horrible) and tiresome(as I always find tweaking the design here and there is just too wasteful for the time, I know UI/UX is important, but I just really hate doing this part myself personally).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After searching around for quite a long time. I found that I can actually just use jekyll to build a simple but elegant blog. To make things better, jekyll is officially recommended and suppored by GitHub. So that’s it. Setting up jekyll, searching for some free HTML template for online Resume(I found a free template by Thomas Hardy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thomashardy.me.uk/free-responsive-html-css3-cv-template&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and the blog site is done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning to write some notes on OOP, RESTful API design blogs as I’m currently reading about these topics and reckon it’d be a good exercise and a great test of my understandings to blog about what I’ve learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to add more features to this site if time permitted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="some" /><category term="random" /><category term="stuff" /><summary type="html">I have finally decided to set-up a personal blog website, although I have, a long time ago, already knew how to build a simple blog webiste. Why so late? Well, partly because of the process of getting a domain name in China is a little bit complicated, partly(and largely) because I’m lazy and don’t want to spend money just for hosting a simple Blog website.</summary></entry></feed>